[Music]
Hey. Hey. Hey.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Well, Welcome back, Living Mana Church
family. We are so happy that you are
here worshiping with us for divine
worship service today on this Sabbath
day. If you were if you missed or were
not a part of our Sabbath school today,
you're going to have to go back and
watch that because it was a recap of
last week's sermon on um 1844 and the
investigative judgment. So, you're going
to want to go back and watch that. and
Pastor Meyer's sermon is going to be
part two to that topic as well. So, this
is a very important topic and you do not
uh want to miss it and you want to
understand it for yourself. And so, we
really encourage you to go back and to
view that. Also, please like and share
this link and put it on your social
media. Invite people to church today.
let them know that uh you are worshiping
here with Living Man Church and they
don't want to miss the blessing that
you're about to receive here. So, invite
people to receive a blessing as well.
Please let us know where you're viewing
from. Put in the chat where you're
viewing from so we can say a special
welcome to you. Put a one if this is
your very first time because we want to
tell you more about our online church.
And if you already put during our first
service uh where you were viewing from,
you don't have to do it again. But
please, if you're just joining us now
for the first time and you were not able
to do that during the first service,
please let us know because again, I want
to say a very, very special welcome to
all of you. So, with that said, I am
just waiting for the first person to put
where they're viewing from because
again, we want to say a very special
welcome to you. And we're just thankful
that
um half of those who were um in the
first program have now joined us because
we have a second link. This is the
second link for today. Sabbath school is
its own link. But okay, we have um
Threshold from Threshold of Hope Africa
and from Nairobi, Kenya. Welcome to
Living Mana Church. Uh Sister Jerry from
San Diego. She just became an official
member today. She's been working with us
for the last few years, but official
member today. So, welcome. Always happy
to see you here. Crystal Cox, you know,
it's always a blessing to see you here.
Um as well, so glad that you are here.
We have, they're going up kind of fast
now. From Barbados. I saw Barbados.
Okay. Blessing Joy from Barbados.
Welcome. Okay, we have uh Nancy from
Connecticut and we're so good to see you
here. Daisy from the state of Tennessee,
our neighboring state. Good to hear you.
It's good to see you here and I hear
you. Um good to see you here. Christoph
Christopher from Wildwood, Florida. Good
to see you here. Um, let's see. Karen
from New York. We have Anna from uh
Aoka, Florida. I think I said that
right. I think I said that wrong,
actually. Aka, Florida. Okay. From
Florida. Um, Ivan Dayton, Ohio. Good to
see you. Jennifer from Tennessee. Daria,
you're from Indianapolis, Indiana. Good
to see you here um as well. And then we
have Back to Eden Ministries. And that's
Eden and from um South Africa. So good
to see all of you here. Welcome to
Living Mana Church. We have Andre from
Toronto. Welcome to Thank Thank you for
being here. We're so happy that you're
here. Again, if this is your first time,
please put a one in the chat so I can
just tell you a little bit of more about
the church, but you're going to hear
some about it in the announcement. And
so, uh, we're just thankful that you are
all here. Vivian from Fagatville, North
Carolina. I went there, actually flew
into North Carolina. Been to there. It's
a small little airport on a small little
plane, but I've been there. So, welcome.
Welcome to Living Manage Church. And
Randy Preston, you're a one. Welcome. We
are so happy that you are here
worshiping with Living Manage Church. Uh
today, it's such a blessing to have you
here. Uh we have Threshold of Hope from
Africa. You're also a one. Let's see.
So, Ry's a one. Daisy's a one. Threshold
of hope is a one. All right. To all my
ones, let me tell you about Living
Manage Church. It is a completely online
um line church. I'm not ignoring the Bay
Area, you know. Okay, the Bay Area is my
my last home before we came here. I love
the Bay Area. Any welcome from all of
you from the Bay Area. All right, to my
ones, Living Man Church is a 100% online
7th Day Adventist church. So, all of our
programming is online. Um and we have
members from all around uh the world and
we are so thankful for that. But we have
programming as you are here with us on
Sabbath. So we have programming every
Sabbath. We have uh which is on Saturday
and which is today and we have
programming on mental health which is on
Monday and mental health Mondays is just
what it sounds like. We talk about all
things mental health from mental health
professionals. I'm one. We have my other
co-host is Dr. Ricardo White. He is a
psychiatrist. I'm a licensed marriage
and family therapist. And so we talk
about all the issues of mental health.
And then on True Health Tuesdays, we
have we talk about everything with
health, right? And we're going to talk
about that what this week's topic is
about. But um we have a licensed
nutritionist. We have two um doctors.
One is a is a MD, one is a naturopathic
doctor who is licensed. And so they
share things about health and healthy
living and lifestyle. And so you can go
u these are live programs and you get to
you get to ask your questions and do all
of those things um for true health
Tuesdays and mental health Monday. And
then on Wednesday we have power
Wednesday. Our prayer team leads out on
that. Uh but now we just started a new
program for prayer on Wednesday that
goes along with Power Wednesday. Um well
there's prayer happening on both of the
programs and that's the power line. And
so it's a live interactive. You you
you're live there. You send in your
prayer. They pray for your prayer
request right then. And so that's been a
powerful um extra component that we have
added just recently to Living Manage
Church. And then on Thursdays we have
practical living with our um young adult
pastor Loami Richardson. So just to
share with you those who are just coming
here today for the first time, we have
programming all throughout the week for
you. Now because we have programming all
throughout the week, we know that your
week and lifestyle is busy. So for you
to stay connected to Living Manage
Church and be reminded of our live
programming that happens all throughout
the week and so you don't miss anything,
you should sign up to get text alerts.
And the way that you are able to do that
is right there on your screen. You can
text 85. You can text LMC to 855. Um,
and that will um be able to to sign you
up to get text alerts. And so again, you
just text LMC to that
855-207-4107 and that will keep you
connected to Living Manurch all
throughout the week. So you will not
miss anything. Now, that's for if you
are here in the United States. Again, if
you're not in the United States, you
can't sign up for the text messages. But
what you can do is sign up for our
virtual church home, which is Mighty Net
Networks. That is where that is Living
Mana Church online home church if you
will. That is our home, our hub, our
base, because all of these announcements
and everything you hear me talking
about, you're going to be able to find
on mighty networks. and the reminders
are there as well so that you will be
able to stay connected if you are
somewhere outside of the United States.
And so again, that's where you learn
about our small groups and you can join
and participate and get to know people.
Our community is formed there on Mighty
Network. So you can get to know people
there um and figure out which small
group you want to join and be a part of.
And just so many great information is
there on Mighty Network. So please sign
up for mighty networks. Whether you are
out of the state or in the United
States, everyone who wants to be a part
of living at a church needs to sign up
for mighty network so that you can stay
connected and be a part of our church
community. Also want to let you know
that we have
Locosc Kids and the leadership that
helps us there. and LMLC kids starts at
11:30 Central time. And you can get your
kids involved by texting kids to
855207-4107 or you can send an email
there at living mana or LOC kids at
living.urch and uh someone will get back
to you so you can get your kids involved
in LOC kids. And again, it starts 11:30
central time and it lasts for about an
hour and a half.
Want to also remind you of how you can
become a member of LivingMana Church.
You see that email there, patrice
livinga.live, you can email Patrice. Um,
if you are wanting to uh transfer your
membership, you email Patrice at that
email. If you're wanting to join by
profession of faith because you've
already been baptized, but you want to
be a member of this 7th Day Adventist
Church and here specifically Living
Mana, then you can do a profession of
faith. or if you want to get baptized by
Pastor Meyers, you need to email patrice
livingmana.live. Um, and so those are
the way that you those are the ways that
you become a member here at living
manana
church. We also want to let you know
that pastor does have virtual office
hours and again that same email patrice
livinga.live live. That is how you will
be able to get set up with Pastor Myers
and to set up a virtual office
appointment with
him. If you are watching on Power of the
Lamb YouTube channel, we would like for
you to go over to my Living Mana uh
YouTube channel, like and subscribe
because we are trying to grow the uh
Living Mana Church channel. Um, and for
if you go over there and subscribe and
like, that will help us to be able to
grow our church YouTube
channel. If you have a prayer request,
you can send that in to our prayer team
who is definitely going to be praying
over your request. And you can do that
by sending them an email at
praylivymana.urch.
If you go if you uh sign up for Mighty
Networks, you can put a prayer request
on uh the prayer wall and you can text
pray to that 855 number. Um those are
all the ways that you can send in your
prayer request and our prayer team is
going to pray over your request until
God answers that prayer. And all we ask
is that when God answers your prayer,
please send uh a testimony into that
email so that Amar can get it. And if
it's okay with you, she can share uh
with the Living Man of Church family the
answer uh to your prayers. And so that
is how you can get prayer requests to
our prayer team. We announced earlier in
our first um in Sabbath school that the
convocation as was planned uh before is
cancelled. It is officially cancelled.
Um and God is having us pivot in another
direction and we are hoping that you
will join us and where go where God is
leading us to. We're still going to get
together. We do not have the time, the
date or the or I should say the date or
location yet, but we're going to get
together and we are going to do God's
work together. And so our fellowship is
going to look a little bit different,
but it is still going to be such a
blessing because this is the way that
God is leading us and this is what he's
calling us to do. And so we are excited
and we want you to please stay tuned um
to all of the announcements and just you
know you you're going to get things
through uh Mighty Networks. you'll be
able to find out information and I will
be announcing um as information is
coming through each and every week. So,
you're not going to want to miss any of
that uh because we'd love to see you
there for the the situation that or the
pivot that we're making, I should say.
We are going to need volunteers and all
of your help. And I promise that we are
going to make it to be as costeffective
for you as possible. So, it won't be as
as pricey as what we were planning
before, but we're looking forward to
what God um is doing moving forward.
Wanted to just tell you guys about uh
something new called Hangouts that
Living Manage Church is is going going
to be doing here and to be starting here
um in the near
future. So, um are you passionate about
building an authentic Christ-c centered
community? Do you enjoy connecting with
others and helping people feel seen,
heard, and valued? If so, Living Mana
Church needs you. Uh, very soon, Living
Mana will be launching a new Hangouts
ministry, and we are looking for
Hangouts to help lead our small group
Zoom sessions. These hangouts are all
about community connection, and
conversation. And as a hangout host, you
will guide your group through fun ice
breakers, meaningful dialogue, hobbies,
interests, and just plain fun. Yeah. uh
you'll receive training and resources,
grow your leadership and communication
skills, and most importantly, you will
be helping others experience real
fellowship within the LMLC family. And
so, we are looking forward to to that be
starting and beginning. But, um the
first information session, as you can
see there on your screen, is Sunday,
June 29th, 700 p.m. Central time. Um so
you are if you sign up for um if you
sign up for Mighty Networks and to get
text alerts you will get more
information about that. You can also
scan that QR code
hangouts.urch. Um you can email um you
can send an email there and you can just
scan that QR code for more information.
So we are definitely looking forward uh
to that. Okay. So, um, we have, like I
already mentioned the power line. The
power line I already mentioned that
we're doing that. So, we don't want you
guys to miss that. That's at 6:30 p.m.
and it's live. So, send your friends,
your co-workers, your family members.
Let them know, hey, tune in because our
church will pray for you right now,
right here on the spot, right? So, we
want people to just be scrolling through
social media and see that we're praying
and just stop and just put their prayer
request in. Um, but you could also
share. We need you to share and tell
people our church is praying. So, this
is a great way for you to introduce
people to our church. Um, and it's like
an evangelistic uh tool as well because
we're of course your your friends and
your family that may be Adventists.
Definitely tell them that we're praying,
but we want you to really share uh with
your your non-Adventist friends and
family that may be going through
something and just say, "Hey, my church
will pray for you. All you have to do is
tune in right here and we will pray.
Just want to remind you guys that Mental
Health Monday is coming back this
Monday. It is our grand finale for
season 3 and then we will return at the
beginning of September, but we will be
we will be returning live, but during uh
the summer months, we will be uh doing
replays of some of the powerful We've
been doing this for three years. So, we
have quite a library of of programs that
Dr. Dr. White and I have done and uh the
mental health information that you're
going to get is by God's grace some
really good information that's going to
help you through a lot of
situations. We also have True Health
Tuesday that uh is this week. U Dr.
Maria Humel will be doing a live True
Health Tuesday and you're not going to
want to miss that at 700 PM Central. Um,
she is talking about uh sugar being a
poison. I repeat, sugar being a poison.
So, you're not going to want to miss
that. Her information has been so good,
guys. You're getting some great
information on to help you make better
choices um with your diet to help your
overall body. Also wanted to announce
that next week, next Friday, starting
Friday at uh 7 PM Central time, is
another Hearts on Fire virtual marriage
retreat. And so we care about your
marriages. Um and so um and we want your
marriages to thrive. And so I am hosting
uh the Hearts on Fire virtual marriage
retreat. And again, I'm a licensed
marriage and family therapist, and I
have helped hundreds of couples
throughout the years find their passion
and rekindle the fire that has gone out
or dwindled to a very, very low burn, if
you will. And I uh just want to tell you
sometimes uh I tell my husband, I said,
I think some and I think I know that I
uh work myself out of a job, if you
will. And that is my goal. That is my
goal. like I want to help couples uh in
such a way that they don't need me
anymore. And by God's grace, I have to
say, and this is not me uh boasting of
me. I really believe it's God and him
showing me how to do things, but I
really um can do it in a relatively
quick in a quick way. Not that you won't
continue to work on your stuff, but I
can train and teach you how to have a
healthier, better marriage. Um and it
does not take terribly long at all. So,
I say that to say if you are wanting um
to just get the to become more
reconnected, to get the fire burning and
with the passion that you had when you
first got together, um and if you're if
you're in if you're in even rough times
right now, this marriage retreat is for
you. But I would just like for for you
to hear what others have said that have
attended the retreat and what what their
experience was. So, I just want to share
that with you at this time.
Hi, my name is Amora Soell and this is
my husband Terry Soell. And we were so
blessed to attend a Tante Meyers Hearts
on Fire marriage retreat, the very first
one. And it was such a huge blessing in
our lives. We learned so many different
tools about
communicating, about um differences in
personality, conflict resolution, the
importance of quality time and going on
weekly date nights, and the importance
of sex. So, it covers a little bit of
everything
um in a marriage that you kind of
identify the things that you need to
work on. And it's it was great.
Absolutely. It was great and a perfect
title by the way because all these uh
tools that Atanton taught us during the
marriage retreat retreat um allows us to
keep the flame burning in our in our
relationship and allows us to grow
together and um you know and that takes
work of course you know I really love
the the the tool about um effective
communication and active communication
rather than passive communication. In
other words, you know, all of us find
ourselves uh kind of being defensive and
waiting uh formulating a response in our
mind while our our maid is speaking. But
what what the tool that she gave us does
is it requires that we listen carefully
and repeat back exactly what was said,
what's being said to us. And that
discipline, you know, it takes some
work, but uh what it does is it allows
you to actually really feel and
understand and experience what your mate
is feeling and what they're thinking and
what they're going through and and it
helps them to know, hey, you're actually
hearing me out and listening. And that's
powerful for your relationship. The
other thing's date night, you know, um
we went on a lot of dates uh before we
were married and and um I can remember
uh she paid for the first date and I've
been paying for everyone ever since. So
I thought, well, I can get married now
and get a break. But no, dates are
important because it keeps the romance
going, keeps the fire burning bright,
and gives you something really to look
forward to. So it's my beautiful
retreat. It's actually my favorite night
besides Sabbath.
So yeah, those are just a couple
examples of some of the tools that you
would learn. Awesome retreat at the
marriage retreat. It's so worth it. I
pray it's a huge blessing to you and
your spouse.
Amen.
So yes, I'm looking forward to that
retreat and hopefully having you and
your spouse there. Wanting you to know
that you could just go to you can
rewatch this if you need to scan the QR
code or go to
newbeginncounseling.com and that's
nu-bounsonseling.com.
Also wanted to let you guys know that
Afterglow, if you've been here for the
last few weeks, if you've gone to the
Afterglow, it has moved. And so
Afterglow is no longer on um on Altter
Live. It is on um Mighty Networks. And
so it moved on May 24th, 2025, just a
few weeks ago. Um and so it is it is
there. So for you, if you wanting to
participate in the afterglow after the
sermon and talk about what you hear and
what you've learned and to fellowship
there, please join us on Afterglow. Um,
but it's on Mighty Networks. And so,
Pastor Myers and I are always there. Um,
and so we're not leading out. We're not
the host, but we're there. So, if you
have questions for him, you can he'll be
able to answer some of those for you as
well. So definitely join us on Mighty
Networks and you'll get a reminder um
towards the end of the sermon to go
there and to join us there. So we are
excited about that. Want to just always
remind you guys about LOC Global. Want
you guys to keep LC Global in your
prayers and um it is just such a
blessing to have Locosc Global is taking
Pastor Meyer's uh sermons and we're
going to be translating the sermons and
some of the Sabbath schools as well into
seven different languages. And so that
is our capability right now that we can
go into seven different languages. And
we just want to give you a preview and
to remind you to go to LMOC Global. Um
it has its own YouTube channel as you
can see down there. Um it down there in
the right hand corner. So if you know
someone that speaks these languages,
please share these messages in their
language. So we just want to give you
guys an example of what that looks like.
Catholic. Foreign
Please continue to keep Alamosi Global
in your prayers. Again, it is a blessing
to be able to go into all of the world
and right now in at least seven
different languages of the world and we
want to grow uh the languages that we're
able to go to all the world with. And so
just continue to pray and you can
financially support Living Mana Global
by going to Adventist giving uh.org. You
can go there. That is where you are able
to virtually support Living Mana Church
to give your tithe and to give your
offering. Also, you can um see all the
other things that Living Manage Church
supports. And so, you're able to go
there. Adventistgiving.org is a great
way. You can even plan your systematic
giving to where they just automatically
withdraw it. I mean, it's just easy.
Sometimes it's just easy, but you don't
have to do it that way. But that is how
you are able to give virtually. So, you
can see your tithe goes to support the
Northeastern Conference, which Living
Man Church is a church um a part of
Northeastern Conference. Um there you'll
see the local church local church um
spot where you can give to that and that
is uh how you can we keep those funds
with Living Mana Church so that we can
continue to do what God is calling us to
do and to be able to do all of the
things that we do like um Living Mana
Global and many many other things as
well. So if you would like to continue
to support or to begin to support Living
Mana Church, you definitely can go to
adventistgiving.org or and the virtual
tithe envelope will show you all the
different things that you can give to.
The benevolence fund helps us to be able
to help people when they're asking for
assistance. So you want can give to that
and so many other things. Uh you can
just go check that out. If you would
like to give uh by mailing in your
tithes and offering, then please you can
do that uh by going to PO Box 428, Owens
Crossroads, Alabama
35763 and you can give that way. Just
please put a note in on put a little
note in there. Let us know what is for
tithe, what is for offering, if it's for
some is for the benevolence fund or any
other area that you see on the tithe
envelope, then please let us know so
that we can make sure that your giving
or donations is going into the area that
you would like to support. And with that
said, we just want to again say thank
you for all of your prayers and your
financial support. It is what helps to
keep living managers going and to do
what we are doing. And we are so
thankful to each and every one of you
for doing what you do uh for this church
and continue to just show up, pray, and
to financially support this church.
Thank you so much for all that you do
and have done for three years. We are so
thankful um excuse me that God has
helped this church to get to where it is
now. And we want to continue to grow and
to get better and to continue to follow
God's leading. So with that, I would
just like to ask you to bow your heads
with me as we
pray. Heavenly Father, Lord, I just give
you praises and thanksgiving for all of
your many blessings, Lord, and for what
you're able to do in all of our lives,
Lord. You are you really are uh a
miracle worker, a promisekeeper, a light
in the darkness, like my shirt says. You
are all of those things, Lord. You are
amazing, and we praise you and we thank
you, Lord. We praise you even in the
darkness. I had a mentor, a prayer
mentor who who taught me. She said,
"Let's praise God right now." And I'm
like, "Right now?" I'm in the darkness.
She's like, "Let's praise God right
now." And it's it's like you love that,
Lord. You love to see our blind trust
because it just empowers you and allows
you to continue to work and do work
miracles in our lives, Lord. So help
everyone who is hearing this prayer to
learn how to have blind trust in you and
just to believe that you are going to
work things out in their situation. And
so Lord, I know there's situations that
are dealing with marriage. I know
there's situations dealing with health,
finances,
uh children that we're praying for. Um
so many different areas, Lord. And so I
lift all of those categories up to you.
And I just ask that you will bless each
person who is hearing this prayer in
their situation. Lord, you know what the
situation is and we just ask that you
will pour out a blessing to them. Lord,
I pray for Pastor Meyers as we are in we
are entering into this time now where he
is soon to speak and to give us the
message that you have given him to give
to all of us. We just ask that your Holy
Spirit will be with him in every word um
and every phrase and that it will hit us
in a way that we will understand and we
will connect with you in a deeper way.
Lord, we ask all these prayers in Jesus
name.
Amen.
Dads, they guide us with strength. They
love us with
patience and they sacrifice for us
without hesitation.
So today, God, we
pray for the expectant dads as they
prepare for the miracle of
fatherhood. And for the young fathers as
they embark on the journey of a
lifetime. Lord, grant them perspective,
grace, and
legacy. For the stepfathers who are
becoming something more than they ever
thought possible. and for the mentored
dads who nurture the hearts of those who
aren't their own. Lord, grant them
perseverance, love, and
vision. For the single fathers who
didn't expect it to turn out this way,
and for grandfathers whose legacy
extends across the
generations. Lord, grant them
understanding, diligence, and
[Music]
mercy. For dads who have lost children
and who carry the unbearable weight of
grief. And for dads of children with
exceptional needs who require more than
we'll ever
know. Please grant them patience,
courage, and kindness.
Walk with every dad as they navigate
life's challenges. When the path seems
too long, and when the journey seems
impossible, strengthen the weary, awaken
the uninvolved, and remind them all that
their presence matters more than their
perfection. May they know how deeply
loved they really are, not only by us,
but ultimately by you.
Happy Father's
[Music]
Day. I'll never be more loved than I am
right now. Wasn't holding you up. So
there is nothing I can do to let you
down.
It doesn't take a
trophy to make you
proud. I'll never be more love than I am
right
now.
Oh, going through a storm, but I won't
go down. I hear your voice carried in
the rhythm of the wind to call me out.
You would cross an ocean so I wouldn't
drown. You've never been closer than you
are right
now.
Gyra.
Gyra, you are
enough. Oh,
enough. And I will be
content. In every
circumstance, you are
gyra. You are
enough. I don't want to
forget how I feel right now on the
mountain top. I can see so clear what
it's all
about. So stay by my side when the sun
goes down. my
own. Don't want to forget how I feel
right
now.
Gyra
[Music]
Gyra, you are
enough. Oh,
enough. And I will be
content in every circumstance.
You are
gyra. You are
enough. I'm already
love. I'm already
chosen. I know who I
am. I know what you
spoken. I'm already
loved more than I could
imagine. And that is enough.
I'm already
love. I'm already
chosen. I know who I am. Yeah. I know
what you
spoken. I'm already
love more than I could
[Applause]
imagine. And that is enough.
That is enough. What is this truth says
is better than
anything. That is enough. I don't need
money or material
things. That is
enough. That is
enough. Lord, you are
enough. You are enough.
You are
enough. You are
enough to hold. You are
Elra. You are
enough.
Gyra. You are
enough. And I will be
content in every circumstance that you
are a
child. You are
[Music]
enough. Here at Living Mana, we bear
each other's burdens. When you need
support or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged or alone or
anxious, you don't have to face life
struggles alone.
[Music]
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of
need. The Lord is close to the
brokenhearted and saves those who are
crushed in spirit.
[Music]
Amen. Greetings saints of the most high
God and welcome LMOC family and friends.
Want to welcome you to another edition
of living manners prayer and praise
time. As always I am here with my lovely
bride Amra and saints. We just want to
say we do not consider it a light thing
at all that we get the opportunity to
serve you in this amazing movement in
this amazing capacity. Greetings to
everybody that's watching today. So
wonderful to see so many people in the
house of God today. Wow. Earlier there
were over 500 people only in Sabbath
school and we really want to zero in in
on that and focus on that. I thank God
for our pastor and first lady and for
the amazing word of God that's coming
forth right now. But we thank God also
for all of you because we are the body
of Christ. We are family. We are one.
And praise God for the wonderful things
that he's doing. Look, want to send some
shout outs here. Um especially to uh
Sister Kayla and uh I mean um Sister
Kayla, you are now a an official living
man of prayer warrior, but you were
dealing with some warfare this morning
on your way to church and the enemy is
trying to keep you from getting there,
but you got there and shared the word of
God. And so we really are thanking God
for you. And you know what?
Um Jerry and and Jerry and Michaela are
now official living man of prayer uh uh
uh members. Uh Jerry is a prayer
warrior. We'll talk about that in a
second. But you know there's an
interesting connection between Jerry and
Michaela. So Michaela is a student with
Jerry and when Michaela did that
powerful Bible study on power Wednesday,
she was uh sharing uh a passage of
scripture and she approached it from the
eight principles that Jerry had shared
with her and she actually mentioned
several times how Miss Jerry had told
them, you know, how to use the those
eight principles and approaching the
word of God. And Michaela, I want to
tell you, you were strong. That was
amazing. It was. and she was so natural
and a matter of fact with it and just
flowed so genuinely. We loved it. We
love you. We're blessed to have you.
We'll continue to pray with you and
support you in whatever way we can. I
want to tell you though about Miss
Jerry. So, we were just doing
a a 24-hour prayer and fasting. I can
talk about it now. It's over and we'll
do it again, but we're going to do it
again here shortly. But, uh so, you
know, I kind of left my phone on really
low. You know, I had to get some sleep
because I had to work the next day. And
I'm going to tell you, the living man of
prayer team, these warriors and warettes
were up all night long manning that that
phone line and they stayed on there
praying and fast. So, I'm sleeping and I
wake up in the middle of the night and I
hear a voice. Who is it? It's Jerry at
like what 3:00 in the morning? Three. It
was 3:06. As a matter of fact, I heard
Jerry. I heard Sister Jackie, of course.
I heard Joanne. I heard brother Jesse. I
said, "These people are taking this
thing serious." And so you can know you
God has brought some amazing prayer
warriors here. And there were others on
the call, by the way. I mean, 24 hours
they were on that thing. You know, I
stayed on there 24 hours, but I sort of,
you know, Brother Terry had to doze off
a little bit, but praise God.
Well, Jerry's always been a part of the
family, but welcome officially.
You're official. So, yes, you are. You
are. And to to all the rest of you, I
want to shout out every everybody that
the entire Living Man of Praise team
have been doing some wonderful stuff.
Sister Diana shared some good stuff with
us yesterday. Such a blessing. We
enjoyed your ministry the other night.
It was so great. Ross and Gina, just
everybody, Brother Elco, I mean, just on
and on and on. So beautiful. Sister
Valerie. Oh, just wanted to just take a
moment and ask everybody, let us say
special prayers for our beloved sister
Valerie. Uh she is an incredible soldier
and she's been struggling with some
health issues, but let me tell you
something. If Val can hold her finger
up, if she can open her eyes, she's
going to get on there and she's going to
be there available and praying and
ministering for somebody. So, Sister
Val, we love you. We're going to keep
you in prayer and just hold on and keep
on pressing on. Amen. Amen. And if
people don't understand what Terry was
talking about with the
24hour prayer and fasting, that is for
um the new power line that just started
a couple weeks ago. We haven't had our
official launch yet, but this will be
our third week coming up on Wednesday.
So, tune in, share with your friends. Um
so, anybody can can uh ask for prayer
and we will do our best pray live on
Wednesdays. Yeah. I'm sorry. You know,
sometimes I guess I just assume
everybody knows what I'm talking about
without giving all the details, but
that's why I'm here. Yeah, that's
exactly why you're here, my dear. And
so, thank you. Um, so yeah, saints, uh,
we we we know that many of the people uh
that we're praying for. We don't know
what's going to come our way. We don't
know who's going to get on that line. We
don't know what they're going through,
what they're experiencing in their
lives. But I do know that when I was in
prison, Pastor Natante didn't even know
this. I only wrote this down and sent it
home to my mom when God showed me that I
would be an intercessor. I thought I was
going to be doing something else, but
the Lord uh he has his plans and he
worked it out. And um you know uh the
Lord gave me that passage from 2 Timothy
chapter
2:24-26 says the servant of the Lord uh
must be gentle unto all men apt to teach
patient instructing those who oppose
themselves that per venture God might
grant them repentance to recovering of
themselves from the from the from the
enemy who have taken them captive at his
own will. And so, um, many of the people
that we're praying for, they're held in
bondage and they're experiencing some
things that the enemy's let loose in
their lives even though he is a defeated
foe until they know that, until they are
educated in the word of God and the
truth of God and anointed and filled
with the Holy Ghost and power, then they
won't be able to recover themselves
because they can't stand up and resist
him with the truth until they've learned
to submit to God. And so, as we're
praying for people, we're taking this
very serious. We know that God takes it
serious and so we want to be used by him
in a special way. We don't want to just
have a gospel that's in word only, but
in demonstration of the Holy Ghost in
power. And so we're giving ourselves to
God that he would use us. And he's been
doing some amazing, amazing stuff,
answering prayers. And we just want to
encourage you if your season doesn't
seem to have come around yet, hold on,
saints. Your day is coming. Hold on.
Answer is on the way. Amen. Amen. Amen.
praise reports, my love. Okay. You ready
for me now? Yes, ma'am. All right. So,
before I get into the praise reports,
just a reminder, if you have a prayer
request, a praise report, you would join
like to join the prayer team or a
special ops prayer team under the prayer
team
umbrella, please send an email to
praymanana.urch.
If you would like to uh request a
special ops team for yourself or a loved
one, please send an email to spec ops,
that's
sops at
livingmana.urch. If you would like to
join the women's ministry on mighty
networks, please send an email to
women
livinga.urch. And finally, if you would
like to join the men's ministry, please
send an email to sevenloaves. That's s
eve ven l o a
vegan manana.urch.
Amen. Amen. All right. I I I also want
to just just, you know, first lady
talked about pivoting. When you're
walking with God, you got to be able to
pivot. And so, and that just just jumped
in my heart really that our tech team
have done some serious pivoting this
morning. Oh, yes. Shout out to Sister
Patrice. Absolutely. Brother Colin,
brother Gavin, and definitely Brother
Joshua, son of of Ivor. Y'all y'all
y'all y'all I'm going to tell you
something. The enemy was after us this
morning with this thing. And y'all put
it together, and it just a it just
happened so smoothly. Smooth transition.
We thank God for y'all. We love y'all
and we're praying for you. We do not
take lightly what you do behind the
scenes just because you're not up here
front and we see and hear you. Listen,
we wouldn't be here either if it wasn't
for you doing what you do. So, praise
God for you. Big shout out for them. But
if you're in the chat, I want you to
just put praise God for the tech team in
the chat today and let them know you
love them that we're praying for them.
All right. Amen.
Amen. All right. Starting us out is a
praise report from actually two praise
reports from Shaunene Wright. Number
one, praise God and thank you for your
prayers. Isaac had an impacted bell on
one side. Even though he moves them
regularly, they removed everything. He
is feeling much better. I am so grateful
for your prayers. Thank God it wasn't a
critical situation. Amen. And her second
praise report is Nicole was released
from the hospital this afternoon. She's
home resting. She has to wear a monitor
to determine her stroke risk. On lots of
meds. Thank you all for your prayers.
And then another update on Nicole.
Praising God for bringing Nicole through
her healing from a TIA, which is a mini
stroke at such a young age. Praise God.
She is feeling better and healing.
Praise God her face is back to normal.
Praise God for the medical staff. Praise
God for all the prayers of my brothers
and sisters. Amen. Amen. From Angela
Perry. Hi family just got a delivery. A
local electric company sent me a free
humidifier. I qualified for it due to
low income and disability. Maybe it will
help with seasonal asthma symptoms. Yay.
Amen. Angela from Annette
Rivas. Glory. Glory, glory to God, the
creator of the heavens and earth. Yes.
Hello family. I have a praise report. I
had court today again and the plaintiff
who is a lawyer did not show up. The
court dismissed this case without
prejudice. Which means the plaintiff can
still come back and sue and reopen the
case. But I trust that the Lord has
touched the heart of this lawyer not to
pursue this case any further. Thank you
so much for lifting me up in prayer and
may God continue to have control over
the situation. Love you all and thanks
again for the prayers. Amen. Amen. All
right, this one's from Artell Peters.
Now, Artell has sent us on quite the
harrowing journey through the DMV. So,
let's see what Artell has to say today.
Yeah.
um preparation day praise report. So
this came in yesterday. Praise God. By
submitting my plans to God and asking if
it is your will, I will be granted this
day that the Lord has made the privilege
to drive a registered vehicle in the
state of G Georgia. thereby giving me
the ability to spread the gospel to all
where God's Holy Spirit directs this
earthly vehicle to go therefore and make
disciples of all nations to the glory of
God was careful that I would not be
found working out my own plans to the
disregard of God's plans. Hallelujah and
me and amen. Thank you Lord. Amen.
Congratulations Artell. Amen.
Congratulations. Praise God.
from Joanne Steven. Now, this one, I can
just visualize her in this praise
report, her voice and everything. Oh,
yeah. It's very animated and I love it
so much. All right. Starts out, uhhuh.
God did it again. Why won't Why won't I
love a being like this? I recently
started working three days a week for
three hours a day. So obviously the pay
is very small. When I received my pay, I
said, "Lord, how am I going to make this
work?" I realized that I won't be able
to pay bills, travel to work, and buy
groceries with a small sum. So I said,
"Lord, you're going to have to do
something." I put aside my tithe. That
was all I spare. No money for offering,
no groceries.
Well, today one of my and Val's friends
called and told me to look out for her
husband and son. They came and took me
to the supermarket and stocked up my
grocery cupboards. Of course, I was very
ladylike and sedate about it, all polite
and thankful in their presence. But I
did bed cartwheels after they left of
joy and gratitude. I praise God them,
their children, their dogs, and even
their shadows. Ain't God grand? He
rolled up his sleeves and went to work
again for his daughter. Hallelujah.
Hallelujah. Hallelujah. Thank you,
Jesus. Praise God. Come on, somebody.
Praise God. Yes. Yes. Yes. What a mighty
God we serve. Yes.
And finally from our newest member of
Living Mana online church, Jerry Harvey
Leonard. We had so many issues today
with our LMOC kids platform. So we
prayed. The horrible echo only left when
the kids participated in Scripture
Keepers and our version of Afterglow. It
was the children who repeated the fact
that the gifts and talents that God gave
were used to sin and that we are still
doing that today. Exodus 32. The
children also noticed that God honored
their prayer. The echoes disappeared
during these times that the word of God
was recited and discussed. Praise him.
Amen. Amen. Amen. Well, praise God.
Thank you all saints for sharing your
praise reports. Continue to send in your
praise reports. Yes, please do. So we
can share them. Uh sometimes we get so
many that Sister Joanne decides that
it's okay. It's time to have uh a prayer
service that's just on just praise and
praise reports. So we like doing that.
That's a that's a blessing. And we
anticipate that as we continue to draw
near and closer to the coming of the
Lord and God's people are preparing
themselves, we anticipate and we expect
that our God is going to be doing great
and incredible things on our behalf. And
so we ain't going to have a room or time
to tell it all. So y'all got to make it
to glory. We got to get to glory
together, y'all. So we can spend forever
telling these wonderful stories and
rejoicing over all the goodness of God.
when we get there and find out some of
the things that he's done that we didn't
even know about. My my come on somebody
and sister Ayana I see you there. You
know I'm not going to overlook you war
yet mighty and we thank God for you and
everyone else I just want to tell you we
see your prayer requests and we're
gathering them in the chat. Uh today
though I you know what for intercessory
prayer I just want to pray a general
prayer today for everyone. Uh there was
a few prayer requests. I did want to
Sharon Fay. We are praying for uh uh
Jacqueline Clay uh who lost her husband
last year and lost her job. And we're
also going to pray for uh I believe it's
Ja Brown who's having trouble walking.
We will be lifting her up. And we're
going to pray for our beloved sister um
uh Deborah Howard. She's from the Shiloh
SDA church in Cincinnati, Ohio. Want to
pray for her. She had a stroke three
weeks ago. want to continue to lift him
up. And Sister Teresa Hatton, we'll be
praying for you and mental health, and
we'll be praying for all those bondages
and demonic attacks from DJ. I know I'm
a living witness. Me and DJ have similar
past. And I know that God can uh heal,
touch, save, and deliver. He can
transform, pick you up, and turn you
around. I was thinking today when we're
talking about our pastor and this unique
gift that he has. And you know, I sat in
prison for 25 years. And I sat there a
lot of times I would I I watched this
brother on DVDs and videos that the the
Seventh Day Adventist sponsors would
bring in and and never imagined one day
that I'd walk out and meet this brother
face to face and I did meet him. And so
you can can you imagine how it would
feel that I'd meet sit there and then
the Lord says, "I want you to stay right
here. I want you to sit here. I want you
to listen. I want you to learn and learn
what I have for you." And that's when
God really began to show me that this
unique gift this brother has is to show
us who we are and what's available to
us. And so saints, that's what our
prayer is going to be about today is for
us that God equip us for this hour.
Strengthen us for this hour. Build us up
for this hour. No matter what we're
going through, all of our storms, all of
our trials, all of our struggles, all of
our sicknesses and challenges and
heartbreaks and and and just, you know,
breakups and breakdowns, all of that
stuff that's going on in our lives. Our
God is greater and he still in spite of
that he's still got a calling for us. We
are the children of God. We are for
signs and for seasons today for to this
world that is uh uh headed towards
destruction. And so I want to pray today
that this message and this word that
that pastor and first lady have been
sending forth this Daniel message this
1844 message this beautiful vision of
God that God has revealed in the book of
Daniel. four separate uh versions of the
same vision and how God is trying to
show us all throughout the Bible. I'm
trying to say something to you and it is
all about Jesus. And I want to thank God
for being so good to us today. Join me
in prayer right now, saints, as we just
go to the throne of grace with our
hearts humbled and broken before
God. And so, Father, we thank you, Lord,
for bringing us to this hour. You have
called us just like Esther for such a
time as this. And we are coming to the
king, Lord. We're coming to the throne
of grace in order that we might obtain
mercy and find grace to help in time of
need. And Lord, we thank you, Lord.
Lord, we give you glory. We give you the
honor and the we give you the praise,
Lord. Forgive us, Lord, for our sins
that we've committed against you in
word, thought, and deed or things that
we should have done and didn't do. Lord,
we have uh uh we know that we have
sinned and we have uh uh uh uh
forgotten, Lord God, our first love,
which is you, Lord Jesus. But thank you
for being so faithful. Thank you for
being so good and so strong. Thank you
that you are greater. You said in your
word that them that know their God shall
be strong and do exploits. Meaning that
we can give praise unto you in the midst
of our storms and our trials. We can
give praise to you, Lord God, when
sickness and disease strikes our body
and when debt and challenges and bills
that need to be paid, Lord, that we
become a candidate that we would for for
a blessing and for miracles as we wait
for you to show up on our behalf and
show up and show out, Lord God, in ways
that we never imagined or thought. Lord,
for everyone within the sound of our
voice today, we pray someone watching
today in desperation. Someone came to
Living Mana hungering Lord God for the
bread of life. Someone came from to
Living Mana Lord looking for a
connection. Someone came to Living Mana
in with their mind in turmoil with
questions and reasoning and looking for
answer. Someone is looking want to know
is this Bible really true? Is there
really hope for a lost soul? Is this
word of God really alive and quick? Does
the God of the Bible really know the end
from the beginning? Does he really know
the ending before the beginning begins?
If I can trust him with these prophetic
words coming to pass just as he declared
it thousands of years ago, Lord, then I
can trust him with my today. I can trust
him with my tomorrow. I can trust him
with my marriage. I can trust him with
my job. I can trust him in my home, in
my health, Lord, in my mind, Lord, in my
heart, oh God. I can trust him as I pray
for my children. I can trust him as I
pray for those in prison who need to be
set free. Lord, before they're ever set
free, God, I know that I can trust him
in my churches, in my communities, in my
neighborhoods. I can trust him in the
ministry. I can trust him, Lord God,
when I can't seem to stop being bitter.
When I can't seem to forgive and let go
of hurt and hang-ups of the past, when I
just can't seem to make it. Thank you,
God, that I can trust you. that there is
still something in this world that we
can trust in and rely on and that is the
word of the living God. Thank you Lord
Jesus for giving it all for us. Thank
you Lord. And it's this on this Sabbath
day Lord as a sign that between us and
you that you are the Lord our God that
sanctifies us as a sign that you have
created us again a new that you've made
us again another vessel Lord as seems
pleasing unto you. as a sign unto you.
We honor you and we worship you today
and we enter into your rest believing
you Jehovah Gyra have made these works
finished from before the foundation of
the world. You have provided for
everything we will ever need. Thank you,
God, that your grace is greater than all
of our sins. Your grace is greater, God,
than all of our sicknesses and disease.
Your grace is greater than the enemy and
the enemy out there. We thank you,
Father, for being so good. And Lord, we
thank you that once again, more and more
you're going to be revealing light and
shining light upon your word. We thank
you for the word that we are about to
receive. Lord, we humble our hearts
before you to receive it today. God,
enlighten our hearts, enlighten our
minds in Jesus name. God, soften our
hearts, Lord. Fill us with love
overflowing, oh God, in Jesus name. in
Jesus name as we hear your word today
father and father some of us have
struggled with something in our lives
whether it be a character defect a
change that we see needs to be made Lord
God in Jesus name we exalt you and
magnify you today above that thing
because we know you are able and we give
you the glory the honor and the pay
praise today and someone who's watching
who may be even in pain right now Lord
someone watching and praying and saying
God are you thinking of
Lord, are you thinking about my
struggle, my specific trial, my unique
thing that I'm going through that nobody
else understands? Show them, Lord God,
that just as you said, Lord, their
brothers and sisters throughout the
whole world are suffering these same
temptations and trials. Set that one
free that's watching, that tuned into
living mana today, Lord. Show them it
wasn't a coincidence. Show them sitting
right there in their living room, Lord
God, or right there in their car, Lord
God, or wherever they may be listening
that they are on your mind, Lord, and
you're more than able to heal, touch,
save, and deliver. And for that, we give
you glory, honor, and praise in the
mighty and majestic name of Jesus Christ
of Nazareth, your son. Amen. Amen.
[Music]
We worship you,
Jesus, God of Abraham. You're the God of
covenant, the faithful
promises. Time and time again, you have
proven. You do just what you said.
Though the storms may come and the winds
may blow, I'll remain
[Music]
steadfast. And let my heart learn. When
you speak a word, it will come to pass.
Great is your
faithfulness to
me. Great is your
me. From the rising sun to the setting
same, I will praise your name.
Great is your
[Music]
faithfulness to
me.
[Music]
Oh, great is your
faithfulness.
Yeah.
Yeah. Gone from age to age. Though the
earth may pass away, your word remains
the same.
Yeah. Your history can prove. There's
nothing you can't do. You're faithful
and true. Though the storms may come and
the winds may blow, I'll remain
steadfast.
[Music]
and let my heart learn. When you speak a
word, it will come to pass. And great,
great is your
[Music]
faithfulness to me. Oh, great is your
faithfulness to
me. From the rising sun to the setting
same, I will praise your name. Sing
great, great is your
faithfulness to me.
Oh, we know that you're so good,
God. We believe you, Lord.
Yeah. It never runs out. Never runs out.
It never runs out. Never runs out. It
never runs out.
It never runs out. Never runs out.
Cuz I put my faith in
Jesus, my anchor to the ground.
my hope and firm
found. He'll never let me
down. I put my faith in
Jesus. My anchor to the
ground. My hope and firm
found. He'll never let cuz I put my
faith in Jesus.
My
[Music]
[Applause]
anesthet
never he'll Never let he'll never let me
down. Sing great, great is your
faithfulness to
me. Great is your faithfulness.
From the rising sun, rising sun to the
set, I will praise your name. From the
rising sun to the set, I will praise
your name. Oh, great is your
[Music]
faithfulness to me.
You're so great, God. You're so
great. Great is your
faithfulness. Yes, it is
[Music]
Lord. Amen. Amen. Uh welcome everyone to
Living Mana online church. uh we are
preparing to enter into
uh the message for this morning. But
before we do, I just want to let you
know that uh we are currently
experiencing storm weather here in
Huntsville,
Alabama. And uh you all know what that
means. There is a possibility that our
power might go out. So, just in case we
uh you you see uh the stream go blank,
you will know what's going on. So, we're
hoping and we're praying that
uh um the storm will not affect our
power. Um but again, if you do, if you
see the power go out, you will know what
happened. You will not be like, "What's
going on?" All right, with that said, um
let's go ahead everyone. Let's uh begin
with prayer and we are going to jump
right into the message. So heavenly
father we're asking in a special way
Lord that you would please speak uh to
your people today Lord you have prepared
a word for us Lord may we hear and may
we understand as our prayer in Jesus
name. Amen. So again, uh, church family,
I'm going to go ahead, uh, church family
and visitors, I'm going to go ahead and
ask you to hit that like button and also
share this link. Uh, let people know
that, um, that a message is beginning
that you believe that they need to hear.
Um, we're going to go ahead, guys, and
and go to the screen. And today we're
talking about the story of Nehemiah. The
story of Nehemiah.
Um 52 days the palace of Shushan part
two part two this is a continuation of
last week's message and uh we are again
going to begin with Daniel chapter 8
verse 1 and 2. In Daniel chapter 8 verse
1 and 2, the Bible says, "In the third
year of the reign of King
Belshazar, a vision appeared unto me,
even unto me Daniel after that which
appeared unto me at the first. And I saw
in a vision, and it came to pass when I
saw that I was at Shushan in the palace,
which is in the province of Elum, and I
saw in a vision, and I was by the river
Uli."
Now we are not going to read the entire
vision today. I simply want to point out
that
Daniel is about to receive the vision
concerning the ram, the hegoat and then
the question of this little horn uh and
this time period of the 2300 days. Uh he
is about to receive this vision. But I
but what I want us to focus on today is
the fact that God brings him uh whether
in vision or in person, we do not know.
But he brings him into the palace of
Shushan, which is highly significant for
this prophecy he's about to receive. We
learned from our message last week that
the name Shushan or the place Shushan is
mentioned 21 times in the Bible. One
time is found here in Daniel chapter 8.
The other 19 times are found in the book
of Esther. And what we learned last week
was that in the story of Esther, you
have the story of King Ahazerus in his
palace seated on his throne. And the
events that take place in that palace,
we learned have a direct bearing on this
prophecy of the cleansing of the
sanctuary. Um, we saw that there was a
king. We saw that this woman named
Esther goes in before the king in his
inner chambers to intercede on behalf of
her people. We see that there is a death
decree that has been issued. We see that
there are books that are opened in which
the king sees the good deeds of one by
the name of Mori, reverses judgment on
the people of Israel. Um and even uh uh
the story even contains lots being cast
uh after which judgment is brought back
upon the head of the one who
instigated the destruction of Israel.
And so we learned uh in that in that
very meaty sermon from last week that uh
the the the mention of Shushan in Daniel
chapter
signifies that the 2300 day prophecy is
in fact about judgment. And there is
something very specific about this story
of Esther which I do not want to point
out yet but I will bring this point back
later on in the sermon. Esther the
reason
uh the palace of Shushan is mentioned in
this
prophecy is to bring our minds to the
story of Esther.
So that is what we did last week. 19
times that shushan is mentioned. It
brings the mind back to the story of
Esther or brings the mind to the story
of
Esther. The other time, so remember I
said 21 times, one time is in the book
of Daniel, 19 times is in the book of
Esther. The other time it is mentioned
is in the story of Nehemiah. Let's go
back to the screen and please note with
me Nehemiah chapter 1 verse one and two.
Nehemiah chapter 1 verse one and two.
The Bible says the words of Nehemiah the
son of Hakalia. And it came to pass in
the month of Shisloo in the 20th year as
I was in Shushan the palace that Hani
one of my brethren came. he and certain
men of Judah. And I asked them
concerning the Jews that had escaped,
which were left of the captivity,
concerning
Jerusalem. And they said unto me, "The
remnant that are left of the captivity
there in the province are in great
affliction and reproach. The wall also
of Jerusalem is broken down, and the
gates thereof are burnt with fire."
Verse four.
And it came to pass when I heard these
words that I sat down and wept and
mourned certain days and fasted and
prayed before the God of heaven. And I
beseech thee and I said bes I beseech
thee, oh Lord
God, that keepeth covenant and mercy for
them that loveth him and observeth his
commandments. Let thine ear now be
attentive and thine eyes open that thou
mayest hear the prayer of thy servant
which I pray before thee now day and
night for the children of Israel thy
servants and confess the sins of the
children of Israel which we have sinned
against thee both I and my father's
house have sinned. I want you to note
the parallel between Nehemiah's prayer
and Daniel's prayer. Remember in Daniel
chapter 9, Daniel is also weeping and
fasting and praying a prayer of
forgiveness. But in Nehemiah's
context, in the context of Nehemiah, he
is weeping and praying. Not like Daniel
who did not understand, hey, when is the
sanctuary going to be built? When is the
city going to be restored? Nehemiah is
weeping and praying because that which
was to be done was laying in
ruins. The work that had been started
had not yet been completed. Put a one in
the chat if you're following me so far.
Remember now that in the story in the
prophecy of Daniel the name or the
palace Shushan is mentioned. In all of
the scriptures there are two
stories that occur with Sushan as the
basis of the
story. Three. The first is Daniel.
The other two are Nehemiah and Esther.
We've already seen that the story of
Esther points to something very specific
having to do with the
judgment. What about the story of
Nehemiah? In the story of Nehemiah, we
see that the work that should have been
completed is not yet complete. Let's go
back and I want you to note the parallel
here to the book of
Daniel 8:9 and
10. Daniel 8:9 and 10 where the Bible
says, "Out of one of them came forth a
little horn which waxed exceeding great
toward the south and toward the east and
toward the pleasant land. And it the
little horn waxed great even to the host
of heaven. And it cast some of the host
of the stars to the ground and stamped
upon them. Notice this. Yay, he
magnified himself even to the prince of
the host. And by him the daily was
sacrifice was taken away, and the place
of his sanctuary was cast down. Then I
heard one saint and another saint said
unto that certain saint which speak, how
long shall be the vision concerning the
daily sacrifice and the transgression of
desolation to give both the sanctuary
and the host to be trotten underfoot?
And he said unto
me, unto 2,300 days, then shall the
sanctuary be cleansed. We understand
according to Bible prophecy that the
ending of the 2300 days was
1844 from the year 457 BC when the
decree is given to start the 2300 day
prophecy. You add 2300 years to 457 BC
and you come to the year
1844. We've already seen that the story
of Esther shows us
crucial information about what we could
expect beginning in the year
1844. Well, I'm going to suggest to you
that the story of Nehemiah does the same
thing. Because remember
Nehemiah is in the palace of Shushan and
he is
weeping that the
work is not
finished. He is
weeping because Jerusalem is still
laying in ruins when it should be built
when it should be completed. Please note
again with me in the book of Nehemiah
chapter 2 verse4 the
king that Nehemiah stands
before now wonders why Nehemiah is
distressed. The Bible says then the king
said unto me for what do what dust thou
make request? So I prayed to the God of
heaven, and I said unto the king, "If it
pleased the king, and if thy servant has
found favor in thy sight, that thou
would ascend me unto Judah, unto the
city of my father's
separ that I may build it." that I may
build it. So I want you to note now that
the emphasis in the book of Nehemiah is
going to be on the work that Nehemiah
has to do. Whereas the emphasis in the
book of Esther had to deal with the
faith of the people and the trust of the
people and the trust of of of
Esther as she goes in before the king to
reverse things that have been done
unfairly and
unjustly. Note the two differences in
the
stories. The story of Ne of Esther
versus the story of Nehemiah. Nehemiah's
work is to build that which has not yet
been
completed. Let's go back to Daniel
chapter 9. Notice with me verse
25. Daniel chapter 9 25. The Bible says,
"Know therefore and understand that from
the going forth of the commandment to
restore and to build Jerusalem unto the
Messiah the prince shall be seven weeks
and three score in two weeks." Now
please note this. The street shall be
built again and the wall even in
troubles
times. Even in troublesous times.
Nehemiah's work specifically revolved
not so much around the rebuilding of the
city or the rebuilding of the temple
because the previous decrees that had
been issued focused on the city and the
temple. The temple first and then the
city. But when Nehemiah comes
along, his work was to build the
streets and the temple and the wall. The
streets and the wall. In fact, in
Nehemiah 4:1, note with me. But it came
to pass that when Sand Ballad heard that
we builded the wall, he was wroth and
took great indignation and mocked the
Jews. So let's pause for a second. I
know I've covered a lot, but I want to
make sure that you all are following. In
the story of
Nehemiah, the the the theme of the story
of Nehemiah was the completing of the
wall. The streets and the wall according
to Daniel chapter nine, which tells us
the streets and the walls would be built
even in troubles times. And we're going
to see that very thing happening in the
book of Nehemiah as they had to
persevere through troubles times. They
had to persevere through
persecution to complete the work that
had been begun that had begun under the
other
decrees. If you're with me so far,
please go ahead and put a one in the
chat.
What I want you to note as we go back to
the screen, let me read Nehemiah chapter
41 again. But it came to pass that when
Sam Ballot heard that we builded the
wall, he was wroth and took great
indignation and mocked the Jews. Why
that is so similar to Revelation 12:1 17
which tells us and the dragon was wroth
with the woman and went to make war with
the remnant of her seed which keep which
keep the commandments of God and have
the testimony of Jesus Christ. So here's
what I want you to understand brothers
and
sisters. The
devil is not only
angry about the temple being
restored. Not only does he not want the
city to be
restored, but he didn't want the final
work of the streets and the walls to be
restored.
Now, I need y'all to catch the
significance of
this because what you will see in the
parallel is that there is still a work
to be done. Praise God for our pioneers
who laid the foundation and built the
city and built the temple and built the
truths around those things which we now
hold as biblical truth.
Amen to
that.
However, according to the
parallel, there is still a work to be
done. And this again ties right back
into
why Daniel is taken to the palace of
Shushan to receive this
vision that we understand as a
2300 day prophecy.
Please note with me. Note with me
Nehemiah 4:7. Nehemiah 4:7. Note what
the text
says. Nehemiah chapter 4, beginning with
verse
5. Nehemiah is praying as a result of
the attack upon God's people as they are
seeking to build the wall.
He says, "Cover not their iniquity, and
let not their sin be blotted out from
before thee, for they have provoked thee
to anger before the builders. So built
we the wall, and all the wall was joined
together unto the half thereof, for the
people had a mind to work." Yeah. Yeah.
Uh like Patty G says, I want y'all to
put thank you to the pioneers. Thank you
to the pioneers for the work that they
did in building the wall. and this
amazing spiritual
city after coming out of
Babylon. But notice what the text goes
on to say, verse 7. But it came to pass
that when Sandbalot and Tobaya and the
Arabians and the Ammonites and the
Ashites heard that the walls of
Jerusalem were made up and listen to
this now, that the breaches began to be
stopped. Then they were very
wroth. So let's just pause for a second.
Let me go back a little bit and I want
you to note I want you to note when Sand
Ballad heard that we builded the wall,
they were wroth. Watch this now. But
when they heard that the breaches began
to be stopped, then they were not just
wroth but very wroth.
Might might this very
wrothness give us a
clue into how the
devil may be responding
today to what that parallel work should
be. Whatever that parallel work is where
the where the breaches begin to be
stopped. Might it be that the devil is
he may be angry with the restoration of
the temple and the truths of the
sanctuary? He may be angry with the
restoration o of the city, the place
where people know to come if they want
truth. But he gets very angry when he
sees the breaches begin to be stopped.
Now you know what breaches
are. Let's go back to the screen. Let's
go back to the screen. So the text says
the text says that the breaches began to
be stopped. Then they were very wroth
and conspired all of them together to
come to fight against Jerusalem and to
hinder it to hinder the breaches being
stopped
up. Which lets us understand now. Oh, I
I see the devil wants
breaches. You see, breaches would
represent holes or gaps in the wall. If
there are gaps in the
wall, those are avenues for the enemy to
come
in. Now, this is very significant,
beloved, because in Isaiah 58:12, we are
told that they that shall be of thee
shall build the old waste places. Thou
shalt raise up the foundation of many
generations, and thou shalt be called
the repairer of the breach, the restorer
of paths to dwell in.
Wow. Wow.
The Bible tells us that God's
people, particularly at the end of time,
will be called the repairers of the
breach, the restorer of paths to dwell
in. Now, let me let me break this down
for you because if I were to ask you,
what is a path? How what would you
answer? What is a
path? What is a path?
So that would be the old English way of
saying what would we call a path
today. So think about it. I'm giving you
directions. I'm not going to say, hey,
you know, you're going to make a left on
this path and then you're going to go
down that path and make a right on the
path that intersects. No, a path is a
road. Very good, Terry. A path is a
road. It's a street.
Thou also be called the repairers of the
streets. I'm sorry, the restorer of the
streets and the repairer of the
breaches. Where are breaches found? They
are found in the
walls. As Daniel 9:26 points out, the
street and the walls shall be built
again in troubles times. Could it be?
Could it be that in the story of
Nehemiah, we find a parallel in
Nehemiah, just as we found a parallel in
the book of Esther, we find a parallel
in the book of Nehemiah that there is
yet a work to be done during the
investigative judgment that will involve
repairing the path, the street, the way
and bre and and
and stopping the breaches in the walls.
And that while this work is happening,
there will be an
enemy seeking to
attack. Are y'all are y'all
following? Seeking to attack the people
whose mission it is to to fill the
breaches, repair the breaches, and
repair the streets. Could it be that
this work will be happening in
troublesous times? Why is Daniel taken
to the palace of
Shushan as a
setup for receiving the 2300 day
prophecy? I want you to note with me
beloved in Jeremiah chapter 6 verse 16
the Bible says thus sayith the Lord
stand ye ye in the ways and see and ask
for the old paths where is the good way
and walk therein and you shall find you
shall find what shall you find you shall
find rest for your souls those who are
preparing listen to me y'all those who
are preparing the streets are doing so
to lead people to find rest for their
souls. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
Yes. Did Jesus say, "I am the way, the
truth, and the life?" Did Jesus say,
"Come unto me all you that labor and are
heavy laden, and I will give you rest?"
Did Jesus promise that he would give us
a new nature and a new
heart so that we would so that the law
of God would be written on our hearts.
Beloved, listen to me. There's a reason
why Daniel is taken to the palace of
Shushan where the two stories of the
Bible that revolve around the palace of
Shushan is the story of Esther and the
other the story of Nehemiah. Listen to
me y'all. It revolves around the
rebuilding of the street that is leading
people to the true rest which is in
Christ which is a rest by
keeping something very special that
Christ gave to us as a part of the new
covenant. But let's hold our thought
there and let's just go to the next
text because we're going to come back to
this. The Bible says in Isaiah 26:1, "In
that day shall this song be sung in the
land of Judah. We have a strong city.
Salvation will God appoint for walls and
ball works. Open ye the gates that the
righteous nation which keepeth the truth
may enter in. Listen to
me. The gaps in the wall. The gaps in
the wall would allow the wicked to come
in. The righteous enter in not through
the gaps but through the gate.
[Music]
Did y'all catch
that? The wicked will want to enter in,
but they will want to do so by climbing
walls, by going through
gaps. They want the reward, but they
don't want what's required to get into
the
reward. They don't want to enter in
through the gates.
What does Revelation 22 20 uh 2 tell us
about the
gates? Doesn't Revelation 22 say
something about those who enter in
through the gates? Are those that do
something? Blessed are they that do his
commandments that they may have right to
the city. Right to the city. So watch
this you guys. The the the repairing of
the wall makes it so that enemies cannot
get in. Those who don't belong there do
not get in. Don't cheat their way in.
You can only enter in through the
gates. Are y'all with
me? Yes. Yes. Yes. Follow. Follow.
Follow follow along. So,
so Isaiah 58 then when it talks about
those who do certain things will be
called the restorer of past dwelling and
the repairer of the breach. I need you
to understand the significance of Isaiah
58 and calling the people of God repairs
of the breach. Because how does Isaiah
begin? How does Isaiah 58 begin? Notice
with me Isaiah
58:1 it says, "Cry aloud, spare
not, lift up thy voice like a trumpet,
and show my people their transgression
and the house of Jacob their sins." Now
you might not understand the
significance of this verse as of yet in
relation to Daniel chapter 8 and why God
is taking uh uh uh taking Daniel to the
palace of Shushan where the story of
Nehemiah would
unfold. Listen to
me. Where Nehemiah would be the repairer
of the breach in that story. where
Isaiah 58 is a prophetic reference to
what God's people ought to be doing at
the end of
time. Why does it start, cry aloud,
spare not, lift up thy voice like a
trumpet and show my people their sins?
Let me tell you why. Because if you go
to Leviticus chapter 23:23, the Bible
says, "And the Lord spake unto Moses,
saying, speak unto the children of
Israel, saying, In the seventh month, in
the first day of the month, shall ye
have a Sabbath, a memorial of blowing of
trumpets, a holy convocation. You shall
do no surv work therein, but you shall
offer an offering made by fire unto the
Lord." Verse 26. And the Lord spake unto
Moses, saying, "Also, on the 10th day of
the same month, there shall be a day of
atonement. It shall be a holy
convocation unto you, and you shall
afflict your souls, an offering, an
offering made by fire unto the Lord."
Please understand that Isaiah 58:1
carries the analogy of the day of
atonement in which the trumpets were
blown to announce that day. The trumpet
was blown on the first day of the feast
of trumpets to announce the coming
judgment.
Why is Daniel taken to the palace of
Shushan where the story of Nehemiah
unfolds in which Nehemiah's work is to
rebuild is to re is to repair the
breaches and make straight the way the
path in the city.
Why does God want
us to think about the story of
Nehemiah as it relates to Daniel 8:3 and
14? Why is God taking us to the palace
of Susan where one story unfolds through
Esther and the other story unfolds
through Nehemiah? Both revolving around
decrees designed to finish to start and
finish the work of the temple and the
city. Why are we being called? Why are
we being directed to this idea or
concept of repairing breaches and then
being told in Isaiah 558 that those who
keep the Sabbath will be called the
repairers of the breach. Those who are
doing a very special work which we will
see earlier in the chapter in Isaiah 58.
You will be called the repairer of the
breach. Why does that same chapter begin
with cry aloud show my people their sin?
Why does that chapter begin with day of
atonement analogy where all the people
of God were to be brought together and
were to look at their
sins? Lift up your voice like a
trumpet. Why is God showing Daniel the
palace of Shushan in preparation for us
to understand the 2300 day prophecy?
Come on y'all. Let's keep reading. Let's
keep reading. Nehemiah chapter 4:9. So
the Bible says, "Nevertheless, we made
our prayer unto God and set a watch
against them day and night uh because of
them. And Judah said, the strength of
the bearers of of burdens is decayed and
there is much rubbish so that we are not
able to build the wall." And our
adversary said, "They shall not know
neither see till we come in the midst of
them and slay them and cause the work to
cease." I need y'all to understand,
beloved, that in this investigative
judgment time period, the devil will
ultimately seek to slay us and cause the
work to cease. But let's keep reading.
Let's keep going. Verse 12. And it came
to pass, it came to pass that when the
Jews which did dwell which dwelt by them
came and said unto us 10 times from all
places whence you shall return unto us
that they will be upon you. Therefore
set I in the lower places behind the
wall and on the higher places I even set
the people after their families with
their swords, their spears and their
bows. Mhm. And it came to pass from that
time forth that half of my servants
wrought in the work, and the other half
of them held both the spears, the
shield, and the bows, and the harbing
and the harbingers harbing, and the
rulers were behind all the house of
Judah. Then they which build on the
wall, and they that bear the burden,
with those that laid it, everyone with
with one of his hands wrought in the
work, and with the other hand held a
weapon. Do y'all see
this? They had two things they had to
do. One was to build and the other to
defend. One was to
build and the other to defend. Beloved,
my suggest to you that God's people at
the end of time have a work to do. On
the one hand, we must
build and continue to build because we
got a work that we've got to complete.
But on the other hand, we have to
defend. Listen to me. We don't have time
to just defend. Otherwise, we won't
build. And we don't have time to just
build otherwise we won't defend. There
is an enemy out. There's an enemy
seeking to destroy this work seeking to
enter into the to the into the into
entering through the breaches and to
destroy the city and the temple and
everything. So So there is a parallel
where God's people at the end of time,
this is all revolving around the work of
the sanctuary and the city and the wall
and the streets. There's it's a whole
package. And God is calling his people
to not only
build with the hammer in one hand, but
defend with the sword in the other. And
now I need y'all to catch this. I need
you to follow this carefully
because in Nehemiah 4 18 and 19, the
Bible says, "For the builders, everyone
with his sword ged by his side, soul
builded, and he that sounded the trumpet
was by me." Now watch this. And as I
said unto the nobles, and to the rulers,
and to the rest of the people, the work
is great and
large,
and we are separated upon the wall, one
far from another. All right,
y'all. Hopefully, I do not have to
preach, preach, preach, preach, preach,
preach, preach this thing for y'all to
get what I'm about to say.
The gaps in the wall
necessitated that the people on those
walls were separated from one another
and the distance was
great. Do y'all catch this?
The reason that the their
goal was to get rid of the breaches so
that the
people, let me say it this
way, as long as there were breaches,
they were also separate one from
another, far away. Watch this
now. They were all on the walls.
They were all on the walls, but they
were separated far one from
another. The goal was, hey, we got to we
got to stop up the gaps so that there
are no gaps between
us. And now you can understand why the
devil, yeah, he's wroth when the temple
is built. He's wroth at the sanctuary
message, but he's even
angrier if he sees the
breaches being stopped
up. Because as long as he can keep
breaches in Israel's wall, there is no
defense. Enemies can just come in and
rob people and come in and take people
out and rob and rob and rob. Enemies
come in through the gaps. And so the
devil knows that as long as he can keep
gaps, he will
even profit off of the
gaps. He will highlight the
gaps. And beloved, I I believe that it
is
possible even as
ministries, pastors,
churches, that we thrive on the
gaps. Because if there were no
gaps, then we'd all be close to each
other. And we realize that we're not
each other's enemies.
The enemy is out
there trying to get into trying to get
in through the
gaps, trying to get in through the the
contentions, trying to get in through
the inconsistencies, trying to get in
through all these things. And so,
beloved, please understand that the
reason that the devil wants to keep gaps
in the church, gaps in the wall, is so
that the workers on the wall
stay separated from one
another. Let's go back to the screen and
read it again. The work is great and
large, and we are separated upon the
wall,
one
far from
another. Y'all need to see it with your
own eyes. Look at it again. The work is
great and
large and we are separated upon the wall
one far from another and the devil
rejoices as long as there are breaches
in the
wall. Note what Nehemiah said.
In what place therefore you hear the
sound of the trumpet, resort ye fither
unto us. Our God shall fight for us. So
we labored in the work. And half of them
held the spear from the rising of the
morning till the stars appeared. In
other words, Nehemiah was like, at the
sound of the trumpet, everybody come
together. We got to have a plan. There
are going to be breaches, but we we're
in the process. We've got to build. So
in the meantime, everybody come
together. So there was still there was
this coming together to defend against a
common enemy. But beloved, let me tell
you, the devil is at work. He's at work.
He's at work bringing people down from
the wall, not to argue with enemies, but
to argue amongst ourselves.
So what the devil does not want is
unity. Because listen to me you guys,
when the people are united, it is a sign
that the wall is
finished. Did y'all catch that just now?
You want to know how the wall is
finished? When the people are
united. When the people, like how
Nehemiah says, I believe it's in
Nehemiah 8, that they came together as
one
man. When the people are united, and I'm
not talking about unity in error. That's
not what I'm
saying. What I'm saying is when the
people understand, hey, these we
We are going to have minor
differences unless we want to make those
minor differences major
differences. We can get to the place in
our church, we have so many arguments
over what what's your position? Is it is
it uh uh postfall or prefall with the
nature of Christ? Now listen to me
y'all. I I I get it. That's a very
important
subject. It's a very important
subject. I believe Christ had the the
the the he took upon himself our fallen
nature and overcame sin in that fallen
human
nature. Not that he sinned, but that he
had our nature and he was subject to the
same uh same things that we are subject
to. He was one of us.
But beloved, let me tell you
something. I think you can be a
genuine a
genuine believer in
Jesus and differ or not even fully
understand. I'm not sure what my
position is on the daily. I think it's
this, but I'm not sure. I'm not sure
what my position is on this thing or
that thing. But beloved, listen to me.
We create gaps between ourselves which
the enemy rejoices
over because he knows he
knows that if we get that accusatory
spirit against each other, we will not
come together to
fight. I'mma stay on my side of the
wall. You stay on your side of the
wall. Listen to this. Listen to this.
Are y'all following so far? The devil
wants to exploit the breaches. Let me
show you something. Let me show you
something. Let's We're I want you to see
how we're moving methodically through
the book of Nehemiah. We started in
Nehemiah chapter 1. We're now in
Nehemiah chapter 5. Notice this. So
Nehemiah in Nehemiah chapter 5, he's now
addressing something very
specific. Very
specific.
Um check this out. Nehemiah 5:9. Also I
said, it is not good that you do what
you do. Ought you not to walk in the
fear of our God because of the reproach
of the heathen of heathen of our
enemies? This is Nehemiah now talking to
his own people. I likewise of my
brethren and my servants might exact of
them money and corn. I pray you let us
leave off this usery. So what was
happening at this time is that there
were people in Jerusalem that were
suffering poverty because of their
fellow brothers. They were exploiting
one
another. And Nehemiah said this
oppression has to stop.
This oppression has to
stop. We got to loose the bands of
wickedness. We got to let the oppressed
go free. Watch this, you guys. Because
if we go back to Isaiah 58:6, note what
the text says. Is not this the fast that
I have chosen to to loose the bands of
wickedness, undo the heavy burdens, and
to let the oppressed go free, and that
you break every yoke? Is it not to deal
thy bread to the hungry, and that thou
bring the poor that are cast out to thy
house, when thou seize the naked, that
thou cover him, and that thou hide not
thyself from thine own flesh? Then shall
thy light break forth as the morning,
and thine hell shall spring forth
speedily, and thy righteousness shall be
before thee, and the glory of the Lord
shall be thy rear reward. And in the
very next few verses, it says, this is
where it says, then shall you be called
repairers of the breach. Note this.
Nehemiah had to address
injustices before the wall could be
completed because they had to work in
unison.
Do you understand that God is telling us
that Isaiah 58's call to minister to the
poor, to the needy, to to to to those
who are being oppressed in one way or
another, whether inside the church or
outside the church. That this is part of
the work that must be accomplished in
order to rebuild the walls, to build the
walls around the city and to repair the
streets.
Check this out y'all. I want you to note
the parallels between Nehemiah 5 and
Isaiah 58. Look on the screen. Look on
the
screen. There were internal
injustices in Isaiah 58 falls fast with
hidden oppression. You smite, you
debate. There was a debt of slavery in
Nehemiah chapter 5. Isaiah 58 says,
"Heavy burdens to be or condemn the
people because of heavy burdens not
loosed. Nehemiah rebukes the nobles. God
rebukes hypocritical worshippers." In
Isaiah 58, there's a call to restore
land and liberty. Isaiah 58, there's a
call to loose bands, share bread, and
bring poor to bring the poor to to
shelter. Nehemiah chapter 5, the result
is that there was unity in rebuilding
the wall. Isaiah 58, you will be called
the repairers of the breach, the
restorer of paths to dwell. And I want
you to understand why is God putting
Daniel in the palace of Shashan where
the story of Nehemiah unfolds. Is it not
because he wants us to read the book of
Nehemiah and also read the book of
Esther and see these two
storylines have everything to do with
the investigative judgment. The Bible
says in Psalm
72:4, Psalm 72:4, "He shall judge the
poor of the people. He shall save the
children of the needy and shall break in
pieces the oppressor." Do you want to
know what the investigative judgment is
about? It is about this verse right
here. The investigative judgment is
where God breaks in pieces the
oppressor, the little horn. Hmon. Come
on
y'all. It is where God reverses the
judgment of those who are poor and
needy, falsely accused.
The judgment is about setting wrongs
right. And part of that work of setting
wrongs right requires God's people to
exercise the same type of justice. Which
is why go when Jesus comes again, the
sheep are on his the goats are on his
left hand, the sheep are on his right.
And he's he's he's telling them, I
judged you based on how you treated the
poor. The poor based on how you treated
the oppressed. Part the judgment.
Beloved, in the judgment, God is
watching to see how you dealt with those
who were falsely accused, those who were
falsely judged, those who were
oppressed, those who were
needy.
H why are we walking around afraid of
the judgment? Psalm 31:9, "Open thy
mouth, judge righteously, and plead the
cause of the poor and the needy." Now, I
need y'all to understand why Isaiah 58
is so important to understand in light
of the judgment because the chapter
begins with a day of atonement analogy.
Call all the people together. Blow a
trumpet. Call all the people together
and show them their sins. Why? So that
they can confess those sins and repent
of those sins and do right. What do you
mean do right? Restore justice. Restore
judgment. Feed the poor. Do those things
that that that that minister to the
needy, to the least of these, my
brethren. That is what the investigative
judgment is about. It is restoring
judgment to the righteous and and
reversing judgment upon the Hmons of the
world, upon the oppressors of the world,
upon the sand ballots of the world, upon
those who are seeking to enter into the
into the city through the gaps and
destroy. Come on, check this out.
Nehemiah 6:1. And now it came to pass
when Sam Ballad and Tobaya and Gisham
and the Arabians and the rest of the of
our enemies heard that I had builded the
wall and that there was no breach left
therein, though at the time I had not
set up the doors upon the gates. Watch
this. That Sam Ballot and Gisham came
unto me, saying, "Come, let us meet
together in someone one of the villages
in the plains of Ono." But they uh but
they thought to do me mischief, and I
sent messages unto them, saying, I am
doing a great work so that I cannot come
down. Why should the work cease whilst I
leave it? and come down to you. Yet they
sent unto me four times after this sort,
and I answered them after the same
manner. I need y'all to listen to
this. If Esther pointed to
faith, then Nehemiah points to
work. I was waiting for this moment,
y'all.
If the story of Esther where the people
were helpless and they could do nothing
but simply appeal to the
king, simply move in faith. Lord, save
us. All they could do was move in faith.
The story of Esther points to faith. But
the story of
Nehemiah, God's people also have a work
to do. And whoa, wait a minute. So, are
you telling me that God brings Daniel
into the palace of Shushan to show him
two stories that are related to the
judgment? And those two stories can
basically be summarized, one in faith
and the other in works. That faith
without works is dead. that while we are
to trust in God and know that he will
protect us, we are also to do
righteously. We've got a work to finish.
We've got a wall to build. We've got the
needed to minister. We've got to bring
people into the city and the temple.
There is a work to do. And faith without
works is dead. And the judgment
therefore is based upon faith and
works.
Oh, that's why he mentioned the palace
of Shushan.
That's why the passage of sushan is the
is the setting for this 2300 day
prophecy because God wants us to think
Esther in the palace. Nehemiah in the
palace. Esther and the people of Israel
having to trust and depend upon the
king's reversal of the judgment. They
were at his mercy. And Nehemiah, we've
got a work to do. We can't just lay down
and just wait. No, we got a work to do.
We got to have the sword in one hand and
the hammer in the other. We have a work
to do. There is the judgment is about
faith and works. That's
why he said, "Daniel, come on. I'm going
to take you to the palace of Shushan."
Now, it doesn't stop there. doesn't
We're almost done, y'all. But it doesn't
stop there because I need y'all to see
this. I need y'all to see this. Come
with me to Nehemiah chapter 7. Now it
came to pass when the wall was built and
I had set up the doors and the porters
and the singers and the Levites were
appointed. Watch this. Watch this. And
my God put into my verse 5. My God put
into my heart to gather together the
nobles and the rulers and the people
that they might be reckoned by
genealogy. And I found a register of the
genealogy of them which came up at the
first and found
written
therein. There are books again. You
guys, these are the children of the
province that went up out of the
captivity of those that had been carried
away from Nebuchadnezzar. The king of
Babylon had carried away and came again
to Jerusalem and to Judah, everyone to
his city. We're going to then it goes
through all the people that were found.
So there's a book there's a book of
genealogies. There's a book listen to me
y'all. There is a book in the story of
Nehemiah just as there is a book in the
story of Esther. and
both. You guys, when I tell you that we
have not believed cunningly devised
fables, I mean we have not believe
cunningly devised
fables. I'm not a magician. I'm not
pulling stuff out of the hat and say,
"Look, no, no, this is right here in the
Bible.
It's right there in the Bible. In
Nehemiah, there is a book with a
registry. Watch this. Watch what
happens. Because there were some people,
let's go back to the screen. Nehemiah
7:61. So after it lists all the people
that were found, then it says, "And
these were they which went up from Tela
and Tel Haresa, Cherub, Adam, and Emmer,
but they could not show their father's
house nor their seed whether they were
of Israel."
Haha. These sought their register among
those that were reckoned by genealogy,
but it was not found. Therefore, they
were therefore were they as polluted put
from the
priesthood. Do y'all see this?
The ones who could trace their genealogy
in the books, those were the
ones. Why is Daniel brought into the
palace of
Shushan to have this vision shown
him? This vision of the 2300 days. It
has nothing to do with judgment. It has
nothing to do with books. It has nothing
to do with lots. What? Are you serious?
It has nothing to do with kings on their
thrones. It has nothing to do with
reviewing one's works. It has nothing to
do with reviewing the genealogy. Please
listen to me. The Bible says in Daniel
7:9, "I beheld till the ancient of days
or till thrones were cast
down. And the ancient of days did
sit, whose garment was white as snow,
and the hair of his head like the pure
wool. His throne was like the fiery
flame, and his wheels as burning fire. A
fiery stream issued and came forth from
before him. Thousand thousands
ministered unto him and 10,000 times
10,000 stood before him. The judgment
was set and the books were opened. Watch
this. Revelation 20:15. And whosoever
was not found written in the book of
life was cast into the lake of fire. Let
me go back. Let me go back. Let me go
back. And whosoever was not found, they
were therefore as polluted, put away
from the priesthood. Let me go forward.
Let me go forward. And whosoever was not
found written in the book of life was
cast into the lake of fire. Beloved,
listen to me. This is not by
coincidence. Listen y'all, this is
living
mana. If you're thinking to yourself,
yeah, I don't know if the investigative
judgment is
biblical. I am not sure how to explain.
Stop. Just stop.
Why is God putting Daniel in the palace
of
Shushan where in both stories of Esther
and Nehemiah there are books open and a
judgment
proceeds both in which result in some
people being retained and some people
being put away as polluted or some
people dying and some people living. Why
is God bringing Daniel into the palace
of
Shushan? Where in one story faith is the
main factor and in the other story works
is being shown and demonstrated as a
sign of
faithfulness. But that's not
all because if we go to Nehemiah 8:1,
please note with me Nehemiah 8:1. And
all the people gathered themselves
together as one man. See that? See that?
As one man, into the street that was
before the Watergate, and they spake
unto Ezra the scribe, to bring the book
of the law of Moses, which the Lord had
commanded to Israel. And Ezra the priest
brought the law before the congregation,
both of men and women, and all that
could hear with understanding upon the
first day of the seventh month. Let me
ask y'all a question. What is the first
day of the seventh
month? What feast is that? The first day
of the seventh month. Why are the people
gathering together? What are they about
to read? They are about to read the
law. Why does God put Daniel in the
palace of Shushan where two stories
unfold? The story of Esther and the
story of Nehemiah. We've already broken
down the story of Esther. But why does
God put but why does God put Daniel in
the past where the story of Nehemiah
reveals a people who are restoring the
wall. There is a judgment going
on. The law is being
read. There are
books. And all of this
occurs around the day of
atonement because the feast of
trumpets led up to the day of
atonement. Come on
y'all watch this now. Watch this. So
some people say that because the Jews
were totally like they had forgotten
about all these laws and now they found
the book. They found the book. They
found the book of the law. Now they're
reading it and they're learning for the
first time. Some people think that the
day of atonement is not mentioned in the
text. So on one hand some scholars
assume, let's see if I can pull it up
here. Here's Matthew Henry's commentary.
So watch this. Matthew Henry's
commentary. We're almost We're almost
there, you guys. The 10th day of the
seventh month between the feast of
trumpets and the feast of tabernacles
was appointed to be the day of
atonement. We have no reason to think
but that it was religiously observed,
though it is it was not though it is not
mentioned. So that's Matthew Henry's
take, but I'll need you to see this as
well. In Nehemiah
9:1-2, it says, "Now in the 24th day of
this month, the children of Israel were
assembled with fasting and sackcloth and
earth upon them, and the seed of Israel
separated themselves from all strangers
and stood and confessed their sins and
the iniquity of their fathers." So, some
people believe that because the the the
Jews were so new to the book that they
forgot the day of atonement and
basically observed it on the 24th day of
the month. In other words, they observed
it late. They they saw the event and
they they they honored the event, but on
the wrong
day. The Cambridge Bible says this on
his commentary on Nehemiah Nehemiah 9:1.
It says uh uh the day of national
humiliation and its religious services.
It must be admitted that if the great
day of atonement were observed at this
time, it is strange that that its
occurrence in this month was not made
use of for the solemn service of
confession. Perhaps this was one of the
commands of the law of which the
stricter observances as of the
tabernacle were now first publicly made
known to the people. So in other
words, some commentators believe they
got the event right but the date wrong.
Why is God bringing Daniel into the
palace of
Sushan where the two stories, one of
Esther, one of Nehemiah, have so many
parallels to the day of atonement, to
judgment, to what we've been teaching as
a church since 1844 and
before. Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow.
Wow. All
right. I know I've been saying we're
almost done. I
know. I just got a few more verses.
Okay. Let me tell you.
Let me be
quiet. Let's just keep going. When you
got to jump off, you just go ahead and
jump off. All right. The nice thing
about this is that this is recorded, so
you can watch it later if you need to.
But I'm going to encourage you to just
stay because you know what? It's Sabbath
all day. It is. It's Sabbath all day.
And there is so much richness here. But
come on. Let's check this out. Let's
check this out. So remember this.
Remember this. I'm going to try to get
through the rest of this as quickly as I
can. So, the wall was finished in the
25th day of the month,
elo in 52 days. I just want to pause
right there. The wall was finished in 52
days. 52
days. That is significant. That is
significant.
Nehemiah when he first starts the work
by when he starts the work from the time
he goes up on the
wall 52 days later the wall is
complete. Do you know that Jesus said in
John 12:32 he said and I if I be lifted
up from the
earth will draw all
men will draw all men unto me. Here it
is on the screen. This he said
signifying what death he should
die.
Jesus went up on the wall. Jesus was
lifted up to do a work. And remember how
in the text uh in Nehemiah it said that
four times they try to get Jesus to come
down. Four time. I'm sorry. Four time
they try to get Nehemiah to come down
off the wall. Four times. I want y'all
to check this out. Let's go to the
screen. In Matthew 27:40, the bystanders
and the bypassers, thou that destroyth
his temple and build it in three days,
save thyself, if thou be the son of God,
come down from the cross. Now, you want
to know what Jesus said? I cannot come
down. I have a great work to
do. In Matthew 27:42, the chief priests,
scribes, and elders, he saved others.
Himself he cannot save. If he be the
king of Israel, let him come down now
from the cross, and we will believe
him. Jesus probably said in his mind, "I
cannot come down. and I have a great
work to do. How about this? Uh the Roman
soldiers. If thou be the king of the
Jews, save
thyself. I cannot come down. I have a
great work to do. How about this? The
thief on the cross. If thou be the
Christ, save thyself and us. Four times.
Four times they try to get Jesus to come
down from the cross. And I can imagine
that four times Jesus must have
responded, "I cannot come down. I have a
great work to do." And do you want to
know? Do you want to know what happened
52 days after Jesus was went up on the
cross? So he was in the grave for three
days and then 50 days
later comes the day of
Pentecost. 50 days later, fire falls
from the sky. And you might be like,
"Well, pastor, what is that? What what
what is the the significance of fire
falling from the sky?" Let me show you.
Let me show you. Come
on. Acts chapter 2. Acts chapter 2 verse
3 and 4. They appeared unto them
clothing tongues like as a fire, and it
sat upon each of them. And they were all
filled with the Holy Ghost and began to
speak with other tongues as the spirit
gave them utterance. Listen to me.
Listen to me. What is this fire?
Zechariah 2:5. The Bible says, "For I
say the Lord, will be unto her, that is
Jerusalem, a wall of fire roundabout,
and will be the glory in the midst of
her." I need y'all to understand this. I
need y'all to understand when fire fell
from the sky, that was God's burning
presence surrounding his church. It was
the wall that was structured around his
city, around his people. That fire
beloved is a parallel 52 days
later.
Jesus
completed the
temple. He also happened to at the same
time inaugurate the temple in
heaven 52 days
later. And the reason I need y'all to
understand
this, beloved, I believe that Jesus when
he was on the cross, he died with a
sword in one hand and a hammer in the
other.
Yes. He was building and also defending
you guys. I I need y'all to understand
this. He would not come
down and he still got a hammer in his
hand. I go to prepare a place for you
and if I go, I will come again and
receive you unto myself. and he's still
got a sword in his hand. Beloved, I need
you to understand this. I need you to
understand
this. And now you can probably
understand why in the dark ages, listen
to me, the Bible says, "And the serpent
cast out of his mouth water as a flood
after the woman that he might cause her
to be carried away of the flood." Do you
see it up on the screen? Revelation
12:15. The serpent cast out of his mouth
water as a flood after the woman. And
now you can begin to understand y'all.
If God put a wall of fire around his
church, then the serpent, the devil
during the dark ages was trying to put
that fire out, was trying to to to to to
destroy the church and destroy the wall
protecting the church. And we are told
that for a time the dragon succeeds. He
persecutes the saints of the most high.
He gets access to them. But watch this
you guys. Watch this. Watch
this. God's end time movement is about
restoring that wall of fire. There will
be a second outpouring of the
spirits. There will be a second
outpouring of fire,
y'all. Yes. Yes. Yes. Put fire in the
There will be a second outpouring of the
Holy Spirit that will again surround the
people of God. It's almost as if,
beloved, the the the the the the end
time uh hh uh uh event that that God is
going to bring upon his church is he's
going to create that wall of fire one
more time around his church. Why? Just
in time for when those four winds are
let
loose. Let me speak to you just for a
moment on a personal level. I need you
to understand beloved that that just as
the work was completed in 52 days,
Nehemiah did it, Jesus did it in a
second dimension. There is a third
dimension for us, you and I have a work
to do. We have our symbolic 52 52 day
period where God is seeking to build a
wall of fire around you personally. You
have a work to do. Your 52 days is not
going to be 52 literal days. Your 52-day
period may be months, maybe years. It
may be your entire life, but please
know, please know that every one of us
who claims Christ has a 52-day period in
which we have a work to do. We better
have a hammer in one hand and a sword in
the
other. We need to be working in
conjunction with the
Lord to make sure that there are no gaps
that the enemy can come in on you
personally.
Yes, there are gaps in the church that
the enemy is trying to exploit, but
there are also gaps in our own personal
walls that the enemy is trying to
destroy. And listen to me, let me come
back to this lineage just for a moment.
Because remember in Nehemiah, what was
being tested was your lineage. And I
need you to understand that the the
thing that shows that you have lineage
to
Jesus is found right here in John
chapter 3 verse 5. Jesus answered,
"Verily I say unto you, except a man be
born of water and of the spirit, he
cannot enter the kingdom of God." That
means to be born of fire, y'all. And
when you're born of fire, it is the
evidence that your lineage goes back to
Jesus. You better make sure you have no
gaps, y'all. You got a gap between you
and somebody else, fill that gap. Go to
your brother. Go to your sister. Fill
that gap. Fill that
gap because the wall is completed when
God's people are united. Praise God for
those for those pioneers that built the
the sanctuary that we now have, the city
that we now have, the the truths of the
Sabbath, the state of the dead, the
three angels messages, the they built
all that. Praise God. But there's still
a work to be done, y'all. There is still
a work to be done. Revelation 14:6 and
7. We're almost there now. I promise
you, we're almost there. We just got a
few verses left. I saw another angel fly
in the midst of heaven, having the
everlasting gospel to preach unto them
that dwell on the earth, to every
nation, kindred, tongue, and people,
saying with a loud voice, "Fear God, and
give glory to him, for the hour of his
judgment is come, and worship him that
made heaven, the earth, the sea, and the
fountains of water." Beloved, this is
the work of building the wall. This is
the judgment. Why is God taking Daniel
into the palace of Shushan? To show
him not only the story of Esther or to
not to show him but where the story of
Esther takes place and the story of
Nehemiah takes place. Why does God want
us to understand the story of Esther and
the story of Nehemiah as it relates to
the 2300 day prophecy? The answer is
obvious, y'all. The answer is obvious.
The Bible says in Revelation 7,
Revelation 7, we got two two scriptures
left. Revelation 7 1-4 and then we're
going to go to Revelation
21. Revelation 7 1-4. After these
things, I saw another angel uh stand on
the four corners of the earth, holding
the four winds of the earth, that the
wind should not blow on the earth, nor
on the sea, nor on any tree. And I saw
another angel ascending from the east,
having the seal of the living God. And
he cried with a loud voice to the four
angels to whom it was given to her the
earth and the sea, saying, "He hurt not
the earth, neither the sea, nor the
trees, till we have sealed the servants
of our God in their foreheads. And I
heard the number of them which were
sealed." And they were sealed 140 and
4,000 of all the tribes of the children
of Israel. Do you all see
this?
144,000. I believe the number is
symbolic. I believe the number is
symbolic. But
144,000 are
sealed. There's no
gaps. The
church has no gaps in its walls. So when
the winds are let
loose, when the winds are let
loose, when the floods come, the
house has been built upon a
rock and the walls will not fall when
the winds
blow. Why is this significant? This
symbolic number of 144,000. Let me show
you our closing verse. Revelation 21:10.
And he carried me away in the spirit
into a great and high mountain, and
showed me that great city, the holy
Jerusalem, coming down out of heaven
from God, having the glory of God. And
her light was like unto a most a stone
most precious, even like a jasper stone,
clear as crystal. Are y'all ready for
this? Are y'all ready for this? There no
gaps in this
wall. Ready for
this? Verse
12. It had a great
wall, a wall great and high, and had 12
gates, and the gates 12 angels, and the
names written thereon, which are the
names of the 12 tribes of the children
of Israel. On the east, three gates, on
the north, three gates, on the south,
three gates, and on the west, three
gates. Watch this, y'all. And the wall
of the city had 12 foundations, and in
them the names of the twel apostles of
the lamb. And he talked with
me. And he that talked with me had a
golden reed to measure the city and the
gates thereof and the wall thereof.
Watch this. Watch this. And the city
lith four square. And the length is as
large as the breadth. And he measured
the city with the reed 12,000 furongs.
The length of the breath and the height
of it are equal. And now watch what
happens when he measures the
wall. And he measured the wall
thereof.4.
and 40 and four cubits. Why? Why is the
wall 140 and four cubits? According to
the measure of a
man.
Okay. So, commentators are divided on
the meaning of this verse. Some believe
that according to the measure of a man
simply means that it it's according to
measurements that a man would use.
Others believe that according to the
measure of a man literally means
according to the measure of a
man. Now I'm not I'm not sure which way
to go and I think both ways have
probably their pros and their
cons. But all I want to say beloved
is it is
highly
significant that the measure of the wall
is
144. 144 cubits,
y'all. That's
character. That's character.
God's people and his city are so
intertwined that the
measurements, it's almost as if the
measurements itself are to remind
us of the
character of his
people which was only
received through the grace and mercy of
the character of Jesus.
There's a rebuilding of the
wall through
Nehemiah. Jesus built a
wall. That is a second dimension. For
those of you who understand what I'm
saying, there's a third dimension in
which we have a personal wall that we
have to build. There's a fourth
dimension in which the church as a whole
has a wall that needs to be built. And
when his people are united as one, the
wall is built. There are no more
breaches that the enemy can get in.
There are no more breaches between his
people. They are all seeing eye to eye.
And there is a fifth
wall. It is that wall in the kingdom of
heaven. No one can climb over that
wall. No one can go through any gaps in
that
wall. In order to enter into that city,
you got to go through the
gates. In every one of these walls, you
got to go through the gates.
A thief and a robber seeks to climb over
the
wall. Why has God taken
Daniel? Why did God take Daniel into
vision into the palace of
Shushan to prepare him to receive the
2300 day
prophecy? Go study the book of Esther.
Go study the book of
Daniel. A judgment is coming. A judgment
is
here. Faith without works is dead. There
will be books. There will be a registry.
It shows whether you have genealogy to
Christ or not. The judgment will revolve
around lots being cast.
the initiator of sin and the initiator
of the decree to destroy the people of
God will
have those sins placed upon his own
head. The Hmon of the end times will be
destroyed by his own
devices. That which he set into motion,
sin. There is a work for God's people to
do, but there is also a faith for God's
people to
exercise. Faith without works is dead.
Esther and
Nehemiah reveal without a shadow of a
doubt that the investigative judgment in
Daniel chapter 8 verse 13 and 14 in the
book of Daniel chapter 8 is in fact
solid is in fact sound and God is trying
to let us know everything we need in
order to make it through that
judgment. If it is your
desire, if it is your desire to embrace
the work ethic of
Nehemiah and the faith of Esther and
Morai, then know that God has you. Put a
one in the
chat. Put a one in the chat. If you're
saying, "Lord, help that to be
me. Help that to be me.
I want the faith of Esther and I want
the work of Nehemiah. I will not come
down till I finish the work. I will put
my head into this work and I will work
as if there is no faith and I will have
faith as if there is no work. Help me
Lord. Help me
Lord. Heavenly Father, thank you for
speaking to us. Thank you for showing us
the beauty and the harmony of your word.
Thank you,
Lord, for this incredible vision of
Daniel chapter
8. And thank you for opening this vision
up by simply pointing out the palace of
Shushan to us.
Thank you Lord for putting these
scriptures into our minds and our hearts
to bring us
comfort to bring us peace to know that
the judgment is about a reversal of a
decision to hurt
us. Then Lord help us not to be afraid
like Hmon but to be bold like Mori.
Help us not to be wicked like the
ungodly, but to do right like
Nehemiah. Help us, Lord, to build the
wall, to stop the
breaches, to repair the
paths, and to be ready for when you come
again. In Jesus name we pray. Amen. And
amen. We're going to go ahead and uh put
the link for our afterlow discussion in
the chat.
Uh it will be uh held at Mighty
Networks. Let me go
ahead and I'm going to bring you guys to
our
um our QR uh screen. And so again, you
could uh follow us on social media. You
can connect with LOC. Um prayer request,
just hit just uh scan those QR codes for
whichever one you desire. If you are
interested in Bible study, you want to
be baptized into the Seventh Day
Adventist Church, um please reach out to
our Bible, our Bible worker at
Bibleworker at
living.urch. And um and we will get you
set up um studying and prepare preparing
for baptism. And again, everyone, may
God bless you as you digest this word
today. Um, this is part two of a series
that I began last week and uh, by God's
grace, part three will be coming next
week. All right. So, may God bless you
and may God keep you.
Amen. Thank you for joining us today. If
this is your first time worshiping with
us, please check out our website at
livingmana.urch. We are not just here
for Sabbath service. We have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health, physical health, weekly prayer
service, financial health, and proving
the existence of God. It is our desire
that our programming will continue to
bless you. Please continue to pray for
us as we fulfill God's mission to go
into all the world with the gospel of
Jesus Christ.
[Music]